Guide to the Association for Union Democracy Files on New York City Labor Disputes WAG.302
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
Association for Union Democracy Files on New York City Labor Disputes
Bulk, 2006-2008
1978-2008
WAG.302
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
1.0 linear feet (1 box)
The AUD was founded in 1969 as a permanent organization to help protect the democratic rights of unionists and considers itself a national, pro-labor, non-profit organization dedicated to advancing the principles and practices of democratic trade unionism in the North American labor movement. The collection consists of case files documenting the Association for Union Democracy's efforts to assist local unions in the New York City area.
Association for Union Democracy.
Box 1
Scope and Contents note
The collection consists of case files documenting the Association for Union Democracy's efforts to assist local unions in the New York City area.
Historical/Biographical Note
The AUD was founded in 1969 as a permanent organization to help protect the democratic rights of unionists and considers itself a national, pro-labor, non-profit organization dedicated to advancing the principles and practices of democratic trade unionism in the North American labor movement. The organization created a national network of unionists, civil libertarians, labor educators, workers rights attorneys, law professors, and others who share the same goal.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Tamiment Library received a gift of the Association for Union Democracy's files relating to New York City labor disputes. The date of this donation is unknown. The accession number associated with this gift is 2009.054.
- Association for Union Democracy Colloquium and Open Letter re: Service Employees International Union, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Gene Carroll, Steve Frasier, Herman Benson: Articles by or about, 1998-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Department of Labor v. Allied Pilots Association Formal Complaints, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Department of Labor v. Allied Pilots Association Emails, 2005-2007 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Department of Labor v. Allied Pilots Association Motions and Settlement, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Does Canada Need Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act?, 1986-2007 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Doug Campbell v. United Steel Workers, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Doug Campbell v. United Steel Workers Case Documents, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Emails re: International Union of Operating Engineers, Feb 2007 - Mar 2007 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Emails re: International Union of Operating Engineers, Apr 2007 - Jun 2007 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 353, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 1739, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- International Union of Operating Engineers Website Dispute, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- John Pawlak and James Stafford v. Teamsters re: Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act, 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Michael J. Quigley, et al v. International Union of Operating Engineers et al: Defendants' Motion, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Michael J. Quigley, et al v. International Union of Operating Engineers et al: Defendants' Reply, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Michael J. Quigley, et al v. International Union of Operating Engineers et al: Plaintiffs' Affidavit and Motion, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Newspaper Articles re International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers, Local 353, 2003-2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Notes Regarding Colloquium and Open Letter, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Press Releases, Public Letters, and General Notes, 1995-2007 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Reform in International Brotherhood of Teamsters, 2004-2007 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Service Employees International Union and Stern v. Rosselli and Healthcare Workers, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Service Employees International Union General Information, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- United Steel Workers Local 16506 v. Mike Williams, 1999-2007 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- "Why Labor Union Members Need Labor Management Reporting and Disclosure Act" by Galen Cook, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)